





tahmid.tf1.dev@gmail.com



https://github.com/tahmid-tf



https://www.linkedin.com/in/tahmid-ferdous-7a66b8134/



http://tfportfolio.netlify.app/

I am a Software developer who has skills and experience in the area of web development and programming. I want to flourish my career in the tech industry; therefore, I am continuously garnering new skills and knowledge related to web development and programming.

## **SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES**

- · Database: MySQL, Postgresql, Firebase
- · Programming Languages: JavaScript, PHP
- Frameworks: Laravel, vue.js, react.js (basic)
- · Front-End: HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery
- Cloud Management Service: AWS EC2, Lightsail, RDS, S3
- Server Management System: Apache, XAMP, LAMPP
- Programming platform: phpStorm, vscode, webStorm
- · Project Management Software: JIRA

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

- Akber Tech Consultancy Lead Software Developer May 2024 to Present
- Inflexionpoint Technologies (BD) Ltd. Lead Software Developer March 2022 to March 2024
- Inflexionpoint Technologies (BD) Ltd.
   Software Developer
   October 2021 to February 2022
- Inflexionpoint Technologies (BD) Ltd.
   Software Developer Intern
   June 2021 to September 2021

## **EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND**

#### B.Sc.

# **Daffodil International University**

B.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering Course Completion: 2020

CGPA: 3.15

Diploma in Software Engineering
Daffodil International Professional Training Institute
Course Completion: 2020

CGPA: 4.00

# **REFERENCES**

Khan Muhammad Nafiul Akbar

Project Manager, IT Agrigate.Asia

kmnafiul.akbar@gmail.com cell : +8801672838306

#### **PROJECTS**

## Bangladesh Forest Ecosystem Services Valuation (ESV) Database

The Forest ESV Database, supported by USAID and the US Forest Service's Compass Program, aids sustainable forest governance decisions in Bangladesh. It compiles data on ecosystem services from various sources, assisting informed decision-making by the Bangladesh Forest Department.

URL: <a href="https://bfis.bforest.gov.bd/esvd/public/">https://bfis.bforest.gov.bd/esvd/public/</a>

### Southpoint BD

Bangladesh's largest Training & Test Centre, spanning 9 acres, offers top-notch facilities including accommodation, dining, and training. With capacity for 3000+ students, it provides training in 22 construction trades, features PE-approved steel sheds, an Atomic Energy certified X-ray Room, and independent power generation.

URL: https://southpointbd.com/

# Bangladesh-Sweden Trust Fund (BSTF)

The Bangladesh-Sweden Trust Fund (BSTF), established in 1984 with grants from SIDA, provides one-way travel grants for Bangladeshi students studying abroad. Managed by a 12-member committee, chaired by the Secretary of the Economic Relations Division, BSTF aims to enhance human resources in Bangladesh.

URL: <a href="https://bstf.erd.gov.bd/">https://bstf.erd.gov.bd/</a>

### Inflexionpoint Technologies (BD) Ltd.

The company delivers innovative, technology-powered solutions to insurers, SMEs, financial institutions, and individuals. Their focus is on mitigating risks in the agriculture value chain and maintaining socioeconomic balance within related communities.

URL: https://inflexionpointbd.com/

## Editable

A dashboard designed to facilitate connections with customers seeking image editing services. This dashboard should enable customers to effortlessly select and purchase their desired services.

URL: http://13.235.133.232/

# Arannayk Foundation

Founded in 2003 by the Governments of Bangladesh and the United States, Arannayk Foundation, also known as the Bangladesh Tropical Forest Conservation Foundation, operates as a non-profit organization. Registered under section 28 of the Bangladesh Companies Act 1994, it functions without a share capital.

URL: https://arannayk.org/

#### Insurecow

InsureCow offers a 360° technology-powered cattle insurance and wellbeing monitoring platform. Our solutions create a digital and robust bridge between farmers, SMEs, NGOs, Insurers, and financial institutions.

URL: <a href="https://www.insurecow.com/">https://www.insurecow.com/</a>

### **Fingerprint Based Attendance System**

A simple and secure attendance system that uses fingerprints to easily keep track of who's present.

URL: https://13.233.140.165/